Hi Georgie, how are you today I'm pretty good today Thank you Neil how are you I am much better than I was this morning Oh
How are you feeling this morning I was really grumpy Oh why is that Well I'll tell you in a minute but that's what we're talking about today being grumpy
Which means being in a bad mood Yes, but before we begin our listeners need to know that they can find a worksheet.
A free worksheet on our website atbbclearningenglish.com. .
So you said you were feeling grumpy this morning I didn't notice that why were you feeling grumpy this morning I get really grumpy if I'm hungry
Or tired and very, very grumpy if I'm hungry and tired Oh no is that how you were feeling this morning then Yeah, it's very hot at the moment difficult to sleep?
Yeah, and we also didn't have any food in the fridge, so I came to work hungry and tired and so I was grumpy.
Oh well I you hid it very well I didn't notice that and I felt cheerful all day so far Well you're always cheerful Georgie or are you I?
No, I'm not always cheerful, mostly I have to say mostly I am, but there are certain times of the month that make me feel very grumpy
And when I'm in a bad mood, I become a bit irritable, small things that other people do annoy me, and sometimes it's not for any reason,
Or it's for a very small reason, and I shouldn't be so grumpy.
Okay, Georgie, what kind of things make you grumpy Well, as I said, there are certain times of the month where I feel grumpy, but other things that make me grumpy.
Usually if it's a really sunny day outside and I'm stuck inside working, that makes me feel a bit grumpy because I would prefer to be outside
In the sun, in the park.
Spending time in the fresh air, but instead I'm working So you said that you're grumpy when you're hungry or tired, what kind of things do you do to cheer yourself up?
Yeah, to cheer myself up to feel better, well, eat something and sleep, but I guess also do something relaxing.
Maybe do some exercise exercise is a really good thing to lift your mood yes,
I, as I said like to be outside that will make me that will put me in a better mood.
Going for a walk in the park, being in nature with some fresh air, I also really like to put some upbeat music on and dance
Around my bedroom, I like doing that cheers me up Okay, I think that would cheer everybody up what if they got to watch it Yeah what do you think about people who are always grumpy
I do know.
Someone who's always grumpy, but he's so grumpy, it's almost funny yeah,
Like he knows he's grumpy and people make little jokes about it and he kind of, Knows he's grumpy so it's entertaining for you.
Yeah, but it's still not really that nice to be close to Yeah, a bit of a negative energy, absolutely.
Georgie are you good at hiding it when you are grumpy Well apparently I am because I sometimes am grumpy and you said that I never
Seem grumpy so maybe I am very good at hiding it.
I think it's good not to let other people feel your negativity coming out of you,
But on the other hand, I think it's also good to share how you feel sometimes okay so.
Perhaps you are really grumpy right now, even though you seem cheerful, even though I have a big smile on my face, yeah, it's because I've had a coffee, I'm feeling good.
Okay Georgie, it's time now to recap the language that we've used in this podcast
Yes we had grumpy which means easily annoyed.
Negative or in a bad mood Yes, in a bad mood and the opposite of that is in a good mood when you're feeling happy and cheerful,
Cheerful is another word we heard today Yes, cheerful is another word for happy.
But you show it in an obvious way maybe by smiling Y, and we've got the phrasal verb cheer up, which means to become happy or cheerful.
Yes, for example, I cheer myself up by dancing alone in my bedroom.
That's it for this episode of real easy English but come back next week for another episode and don't forget you can find a free transcript and works to practice what you've on our websitelearninglish.com. .